sonystyle.com 2011-06-09

# 

Sony Electronics Inc. 

> > > > > > >   | Effective: June 2001  
>>>>>>> ---|---  
>>>>>>>   | Last Update: May 2010  
  
**Your Privacy**

At Sony, we believe you have a right to know what type of information we may collect when you interact with us and our practices with respect to that information. The guidelines contained herein apply only to information collected by or for Sony Electronics Inc. and the entities it controls (collectively, "SEL"). This includes, among other things, websites operated by or for SEL, most of which contain "sel.sony.com" or "sonystyle.com" in their URLs (“Sites”). Websites which are linked to/from these Sites (including websites of other Sony affiliated companies, e.g., Sony Music Entertainment, Sony Pictures Entertainment, Sony Computer Entertainment America) and via banner ads may have different policies; therefore, please review the privacy policy notices on those websites for details. 

While SEL does not generally require that you provide us with personally identifiable information (for example, in order to visit and use the SEL Sites), please note that in order to participate in some activities, it will be necessary for you to provide such information. If you choose not to provide it for those activities, you may not be able to participate in them. 

**Notice to California Residents . Your California Privacy Rights** : California resident, you have the right to receive: a) information identifying any third party company(ies) to whom Sony Electronics Inc. may have disclosed, within the previous calendar year, personal information pertaining to you and your family for that company’s direct marketing purposes; and b) a description of the categories of personal information disclosed. To obtain such information, please email your request to [Privacy@am.sony.com](mailto:Privacy@am.sony.com).

**Collection of Information:**

**_SEL may ask you to provide Personal Information,_** meaning individually identifiable information, such as your email address, name, mailing address, telephone number, social security number, credit card number, or persistent identifier (such as a customer number held in a cookie) which is associated with individually identifiable information, to, among other things, enable you to participate in contests, chat rooms, on bulletin boards, to obtain product or service support, to fill out a registration, to download certain software or to order products and services. SEL may combine the information you provide with other information we may collect from you or your devices or from third parties so that we can more effectively tailor our Sites, services and offerings to you. 

**_SEL will not share the Personal Information you provide with any other parties, except_** (a) to other Sony "Affiliates" (i.e., (i) Sony Corporation, (ii) any company of which 50% or more of its outstanding shares are owned by Sony Corporation, directly or indirectly, and (iii) any company with the name "SONY" as a part of its trade name) who may want to contact you about products, services or other offerings that may be of interest to you (SEL and such Affiliates being collectively referred to as "Sony"), (b) with your consent (see below), (c) as may be required by law or court order, (d) to persons or companies SEL engages to carry out or provide support for our products and services or for the operation of our Sites or our business (in connection with joint marketing arrangements, co-branded relationships, or otherwise), (e) to appropriate third parties, including law enforcement or other government agencies, in connection with a criminal investigation, fraud prevention, or other legal action or if SEL reasonably believes it is necessary to do so to protect SEL, its customers, or the public, or (f) to Borders Properties, Inc. in connection with the eBook Service as set forth in the Supplement to this Privacy Policy at the end of this Privacy Policy. SEL may also provide data from transactions that it believes to be fraudulent to third parties that provide fraud prevention services to SEL and other merchants.

**Co-Branded Sites.** When you visit or use a part of any website that is co-branded (i.e., including both Sony and non-Sony branding) or that is a part of a joint promotion involving SEL and one or more third parties (each a "Co-Branded Party"), you are providing and consenting to provide and are transmitting the Personal Information and other information collected, provided or obtained to SEL and to each of the Co-Branded Parties involved, without any other notice or further consent. Please note that we do not control any Co-Branded Parties’ use or treatment of information you provide to them and you should consult each of their privacy policies or any separate Co-Branded privacy policy posted on or linked from the Co-Branded Site to determine your rights with respect to their use and treatment of your information. You will need to communicate with us and each Co-Branded Party directly, as applicable, if you decide you no longer wish to receive communications or if you wish to change any information you have supplied. 

**_Unless you instruct us otherwise,_** SEL may contact you to provide information about products, services, promotions, contests, or other activities or offerings that may be of interest to you. You can instruct us whether or not you wish to receive such information by checking or unchecking the box indicating your preference, as applicable, at the place where your information is collected. In addition, with each commercial email you receive from SEL or any of its business units, you will be given the opportunity to indicate if you do not wish to receive future commercial emails from SEL or the SEL business unit which sent it to you.

You can also click below to adjust your communication preferences: 

* To opt out of information related to consumer products, click [_here._](http://products.sel.sony.com/SEL/legal/choice.html)

* To opt out of information related to professional products, click [_here._](http://sonyleadmgmt.com/email_opt_out.html)

* To opt out of eBook Store newsletters and information, visit the "My Account" section of your _[eBook Store from Sony ](http://ebookstore.sony.com/)_ and revise your email preferences.

* To adjust your preferences related to Sony Creative Software products, click [_here._](http://www.sonycreativesoftware.com/mailprefs)

**_With your consent,_** SEL may share your Personal Information with third parties outside of the Sony group of companies who may want to contact you about products, services or other offerings that may be of interest to you. SEL will seek to obtain your consent at the place where the information is collected either by an "opt-out" or "opt-in" method, or by other means (such as an email request). Each of these companies may have their own privacy policies. We do not control and are not responsible for these other parties, their privacy policies or their use or treatment of your Personal Information or other information. We and our Affiliates make no representation regarding how any third parties use, manage, store, treat or maintain your Personal Information or other information and you should therefore carefully review all such third parties' privacy policies. If you consent to receiving communications from any of these third parties, you will need to communicate with them directly if you later decide that you no longer wish to receive their communications. Except as to the eBook Service (see Supplement below), if you wish to withdraw your consent from any further sharing of your Personal Information with non-affiliated third parties for marketing purposes you may do so by clicking on the link(s) provided above and providing the requested information.

**For instructions on how to request changes to the Personal Information you have provided to SEL,** please send an email to: [_Privacy@am.sony.com_](mailto:Privacy@am.sony.com) or write to us at:  Sony Electronics Inc.   
---  
Personal Information Management Office  
1 Sony Drive, MD 1E4   
Park Ridge, New Jersey 07656  
  
**System Information.** We may collect your computers', network enabled devices’, systems' and/or networks' IP addresses and message information for system administration, record keeping, capacity planning, volume and other operational reasons, as well as for advertising and royalty reporting as necessary in the conduct of our business. When you use our services, our systems may record this information, which may be stored with your registration, order or other information you provide to us. This may allow us, among other things, to determine which other websites linked you to us.

We collect and maintain Personal Information and/or other information about visitors to our Sites, devices and users of devices that access or use our services and Sites, as well as anyone who sends us information or communications, and recipients of our communications. Much of this information we may gather directly by asking (e.g., hobbies, interests, purchasing habits, music preferences, difficulties in using a particular feature), but we also use technology to collect anonymous information, for example, regarding the content you view through our Sites, products and services and the devices you use to connect to them. We use such information to, among other things, enhance and customize our Sites and services and the advertising and promotions we make available to attempt to create a better experience. We also aggregate information (meaning it does not identify any individual) to analyze trends and statistics to improve your online experiences, our Sites, services, and customer support. If you visit or use the Sites or have registered or provided us with Personal Information about yourself, it is likely that "cookies" allow us to identify you and associate you with your registration, your devices, your applicable Account, user name or ID, information and preferences. For a description of how we use "cookies" see the section below entitled "Cookies."

**Device ID.** Some of the applications used in connection with our products and services generate a device identification ("ID") value during installation or use. This is a number that serves to identify your computer or other device (e.g., for licensing purposes), and which contains no specific information about you, your device, or any files or other data on your system. Among other things, these ID values serve as an effective way to combat software piracy. 

**Cookies.** When you visit any of our Sites, advertisements appearing thereon, use one or more of our services, or receive emails from SEL, we may use technology commonly referred to as a "cookie" which stores small bits of data on your computer. While actual "cookie" technology is currently among the most common, we may use a wide variety of technological tools, means and mechanisms (e.g., XML technology, clickstream data, etc.) to help us to customize your experience to better match your interests and preferences and otherwise improve and enhance the services we provide. We will use the term "cookie" to refer to any and or all of these tools, means and mechanisms, whether they are currently available and in use, developed or discovered in the future or otherwise. We use cookies in a variety of ways. For example, we use cookies to save your user ID, Account number or other information (so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit or use our services) and to help us keep count of your return visits to our Sites and, in some cases, to our advertisers' or partners' or co-branded websites, which helps us determine which services, promotions, features, content and functions users like best. In general, browsers or separately purchased software tools may allow you to erase cookies from your hard drive. You acknowledge and understand that erasing cookies may limit or restrict your ability to use any or all the features and functions of our Sites, Co-Branded Sites and services. In particular and without limiting the foregoing, if you block your cookies, you will not be able to use the eBook Service (described in the Supplement to this Privacy Policy, below). We may also use technology to detect the absence or presence of any versions of software or software updates installed on your computer and to track and monitor content you are downloading, streaming, using or otherwise accessing. Any or all of these activities can occur periodically or when necessary, without any other specific notice to you. We may also use cookies to identify your computer each time we automatically update or attempt to update your software. Cookies allow us to transmit and arrange for automatic installation of updates, modifications and even full re-installations of software on your computer to address security, digital rights management, interoperability or performance issues or to enhance the range of features and functions available through our Sites. Any or all of these activities can occur periodically or when necessary, without any other specific notice to you. 

**Third Party Ads and Personal Information** Without limiting or amending any other provisions or terms described in our Privacy Policy, you should be aware that on some of our Sites, we use third parties to post and serve advertisements. Some of these third parties (e.g., Google’s AdSense) use their own cookies and/or other technology to collect information about you and your visit to our Site(s) and your use of our services. We do not always control the advertisements you may see and while these third parties do not collect Personal Information about you (such as name, address, telephone number or email), they may collect other data (e.g., ‘context-related’ information such as which browser is being used, which domain you came to our Sites from, and what time and which pages are being accessed on our Sites, and other websites you may visit before or after leaving our Sites) and system information such as IP addresses. If you would like more information about Google’s AdSense - including whether and how this information may be used by Google, [click here.](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) Your continued use of our Sites and services will constitute your agreement to this Privacy Policy and the data collection and advertising practices that apply when you use our services or visit our Sites. 

**Research and Tracking Techniques.** Web beacons, pixel tags, passive capture technologies or other technologies may be used by SEL, third parties we engage or third party application providers for purposes such as researching and tracking certain usage, site interaction, and other activities on our Sites, on certain network enabled devices, and in emails you receive from us. Information collected through these technologies is typically in an aggregate, non-personally identifiable form. However, in some cases, the information collected may include personally identifiable information provided by the user where it is deemed advantageous to collect such information for purposes such as improving the usability of our Sites, providing customer support, and enabling users to access third party content and applications. 

**Use and Disclosure of Anonymous Aggregated Information**

Anonymous information about you, such as your hobbies, interests, purchases, music and viewing preferences, downloads, burns, transfers, page visits and other information related to your user activity may be collected, and in some cases aggregated, by SEL and/or third parties whose applications you may access through your devices. This data can then be used to, among other things, tailor promotions, advertising, and communications that may be relevant to you. Such anonymous information may also be shared with advertisers, business partners, sponsors, licensors, content rights holders and other third parties, for example, to inform them about demographics or content preferences of visitors to our Sites and users of our products, or to ensure proper royalty reporting. 

**Security**

SEL takes reasonable commercial precautions in maintaining the security of your Personal Information and in preventing unauthorized access to it through the use of appropriate technology and internal procedures. However, SEL cannot and does not guarantee that unauthorized access will never occur or that any communications means will be uninterrupted, error free or not intercepted by others improperly and without authorization. 

**Notice To/Regarding Children Under the Age of 13**

SEL believes that children using the Internet require special protection, and we urge parents or guardians to explain Internet safety to their children. Parents are urged to spend time online with their children to become familiar with the types of content available on the SEL Sites and the Internet in general. Control tools are available from online services and software manufacturers to help create a safer environment for children. 

If you are under 13 years of age, you should not provide any Personal Information (for example, your last name, home address or e-mail address) on these Sites without the knowledge and permission of your parent or guardian. If SEL learns that you are under 13 years of age, SEL will not maintain or use any Personal Information about you without the verifiable consent of your parent or guardian, except as allowed by law. This may mean that you will be unable to participate in some activities on the Sites without that verifiable consent. If a child under 13 years of age wishes to participate in any SEL Site activity, or wishes to take advantage of a product or service offering available to children, and to do so necessitates the furnishing of any of the child's Personal Information, please note the following: 

(i) The name, address, telephone number, and email address of the operator collecting or maintaining Personal Information from children through this website are as follows:

Sony Electronics Inc.   
---  
1 Sony Drive, MD 1E4  
Park Ridge, New Jersey 07656  
Telephone: 201-930-4800  
e-mail address: Privacy@am.sony.com  
  
(ii) The types of Personal Information collected from children may include the name, email address, home address, telephone number and/or any other information reasonably necessary for the child to participate in a particular activity. This information may be collected directly and/or passively (e.g., through a Web server that automatically recognizes and stores information such as a visitor's IP address/domain name combination).

(iii) The information collected may be used for purposes such as fulfillment of a requested transaction, record keeping, marketing back to the child, or making it publicly available through a chat room or by other means.

(iv) Unless specific consent is obtained from the child's parent or guardian, the child's Personal Information will not be disclosed to third parties who are not contractors hired to carry out the internal operations of the Sites, other than as may be required or permitted by law. We have required, or will require, such contractors to agree to use Personal Information of Site visitors only for the purposes of carrying out these operations and to keep such information confidential. A parent or guardian has the option of consenting to the collection and use of the child's Personal Information without consenting to the disclosure of that information to third parties.

(v) SEL is prohibited from conditioning a child's participation in an activity on the child's disclosing more Personal Information than is reasonably necessary to participate in such activity; and

(vi) A parent can review and request deletion of the child's Personal Information, can refuse to permit further collection or use of the child's information, and can revoke or limit consents previously given. For instructions on how to do so, please send an email to:

Privacy@am.sony.com or write to us at:   
---  
Sony Electronics Inc.  
1 Sony Drive  
MD 1E4  
Park Ridge, New Jersey 07656  
  
Except as permitted by law, before any collection of a child's Personal Information takes place at a Site directed to children or where SEL is knowingly collecting children's Personal Information, the child will be asked to provide his/her parent's or guardian's e-mail address so that SEL can contact the child's parent or guardian. SEL will then send an email (the "Initial Notification") to the parent/guardian indicating, among other things, the information that the child is requested to provide, the intended use(s) of the information and information on how the parent/guardian can, at their election, delete the child's information from SEL's database or records. Upon receipt of the Initial Notification, a parent or guardian may respond back to SEL to grant his/her consent or to deny consent in which case SEL will delete the parent/guardian's email address and any other Personal Information, if any, previously obtained for securing parental consent. Upon SEL's receipt of the parent/guardian consent, SEL will send a confirming email to the parent/guardian's email address or take such other action as may be required to verify the consent.

If SEL desires to use a child's information for purposes other than that for which the parent/guardian consent was previously given, SEL will not do so without first getting the parent/guardian consent. 

**Consent to Processing:**

By providing any Personal Information to SEL, all persons, including without limitation persons in the member states of the European Union, fully understand and unambiguously consent to the collection and processing of such information in the United States of America, and/or in territories or countries outside of the United States of America, and understand and acknowledge their consent, notwithstanding that some governmental authorities may consider the level of protection of such data in the United States not equivalent to that required within the European Union or any other jurisdiction. 

**Consent to Assignment:**

By providing any Personal Information to SEL, you will be deemed to have consented to SEL's disclosure and transfer to, as well as the use by, (a) any party who acquires all or any portion of any SEL service or business unit, whether through merger, acquisition, assignment, or sale, of your Personal Information or other information about you that we have obtained and that is governed by this Privacy Policy and which is related to such service or business unit ; and (b) any party who acquires all or substantially all of the assets of SEL, whether through merger, acquisition, assignment or sale, of your Personal Information or other information about you that we have obtained and that is governed by this Privacy Policy. 

**Your Communications:**

We may, but we do not have an obligation to, monitor your communications, such as messages, to, from, within or directly related to our services and Sites to ensure that our policies regarding use and our terms and conditions are being complied with and not being violated (e.g., no obscenity, defamation or abusive language, no content that may infringe rights), and we have the right to block, remove and/or report any such communications and activities as appropriate. We may keep records of users' messages and, among other things, the email addresses involved. 

**Links to Other Websites:**

From time to time we may offer links to other websites from our Sites. Other websites may also reference, advertise, or link to our Sites. However, we do not endorse or sponsor other websites, are not responsiblefor the privacy policies, practices or the content of such websites, expressly disclaim any statements or assertions made on such websites, and deny all liability associated with your use of, and the content on, such other websites. You may arrive at one of these websites through clicking on a banner advertisement, as part of a co-branding arrangement, or simply by selecting a link on any of our Site pages. These websites might issue their own cookies or collect Personal Information, so please use caution when visiting an external website. You should also be aware we sometimes permit third parties to offer subscription and registration-based services on our services. We are not responsible for the actions or policies of such third parties with respect to Personal Information or other information you may give them, and you should carefully read and understand the applicable privacy policy whenever you provide Personal Information to anyone. 

**Policy Governs Use: Changes to Privacy Policy**

The terms of this Privacy Policy will govern the use of any information collected while it is in place. SEL reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time, so please re-visit this page often. In case of any material change, we will change the "Last Update Date" in this Privacy Policy and/or post a notice on the Sites. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective as of the stated "Last Update Date" and your continued use of the sites on or after the "Last Update Date" will constitute acceptance of, and agreement to be bound by, those changes. 

**Questions:**

If you have any questions or comments about our Personal Information practices or about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to send us an email at [_Privacy@am.sony.com_](mailto:Privacy@am.sony.com) or write us at:

Sony Electronics Inc.  
---  
Personal Information Management Office  
1 Sony Drive  
MD 1E4  
Park Ridge, New Jersey 07656  
  
If you have questions regarding products or services, please click [_here_](http://esupport.sony.com/) for further information.

** Supplement to Sony Electronics Inc. Privacy Policy **

** for Users of The eBook Store From Sony **

1\. If you are a user of (i) the Sony eBook Service, (ii) the eBook Store from Sony at Borders; (iii) any content of the Service, (iv) or any associated websites (the foregoing being collectively referred to herein as the "Services"), then, in addition to the terms of the Privacy Policy set forth above, the following terms ("Supplemental Terms") shall apply with respect to the Services. These Supplemental Terms do not apply to any other software, websites, services, goods, or materials (tangible or intangible), even if they are Sony branded or are linked to/from the Services. Terms not otherwise defined herein are defined in Section 5.1. If you are a user of (i) the Sony eBook Service, (ii) the eBook Store from Sony at Borders; (iii) any content of the Service, (iv) or any associated websites (the foregoing being collectively referred to herein as the "Services"), then, in addition to the terms of the Privacy Policy set forth above, the following terms ("Supplemental Terms") shall apply with respect to the Services. These Supplemental Terms do not apply to any other software, websites, services, goods, or materials (tangible or intangible), even if they are Sony branded or are linked to/from the Services. Terms not otherwise defined herein are defined in Section 5.

It is important to note that some of the Services are made available to you by both us and our partner, Borders Properties, Inc. ("Borders"), on a joint basis. Therefore, when you take certain actions, you may be participating in such joint offerings and your Personal Information and other information that we previously or thereafter obtained from you (or that you previously or thereafter provided to us) in accordance with this Privacy Policy will also be provided to Borders. 

If your Personal Information or other information is provided to Borders, Borders may use, manage, and maintain your Personal Information and other information in accordance with Borders’ own privacy policy. By agreeing to this Privacy Policy, you also agree to the terms of the Borders privacy policy if you now or later take any of those actions identified in the "The eBook Store from Sony at Borders" Section of these Supplemental Terms (see Section 3 below for additional detail). 

We, however, will always use your Personal Information and other information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Your credit or debit card account number, expiration date, and account security number, which you may provide to us, will never be provided to Borders unless you expressly provide your consent. 

If you take an action that causes you to be registered with The eBook Store from Sony at Borders and no longer want Borders to have your Personal Information, you must contact Borders to make that request. Please note that if Borders does not have access to your Personal Information, then you may not be able to participate in offerings or purchase products that may be specific to our joint offerings with Borders. 

2. _ **Special Notice to Parents Regarding Children Under 13.,**_

We recognize the sensitivity of Personal Information concerning children under the age of 13 and are committed to complying with all applicable laws and regulations regarding the collection, storage and use of Personal Information concerning children under the age of 13, including the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act. 

**We do not intentionally target, collect, store or use any Personal Information or other information from anyone under 13.** We do not and will not intentionally collect, maintain, store, use or disclose such information. If you are under 13, you should not use our Services or enter or otherwise provide any Personal Information or other information about yourself through our Services. If you are a parent or guardian who knows or has discovered your child under the age of 13 has submitted his or her Personal Information or other information without your consent, permission or authorization, once we verify you are the child's parent or legal guardian, upon request, we will remove your child's Personal Information or other information from our database. To request removal of your child's Personal Information and other information, email us at privacy@am.sony.com and be sure to include the same user name, email address and password your child submitted. If you don't know or are not sure, please so state in your email. 

**3. _Sharing Your Personal Information with Borders._**

**The eBook Store from Sony at Borders.** Through The eBook Store from Sony at Borders, we and Borders jointly make certain offerings available to you. If you participate in these offerings, then your Personal Information and other information may be provided to Borders. More specifically, there are certain discrete actions that if taken by you will result in your Personal Information or other information that is previously and thereafter provided by you or collected from you in accordance with this Privacy Policy also being provided to Borders. These actions are as follows: 

(i)you register through The eBook Store From Sony at Borders, which is jointly brought to you by us and Borders (you will know you are doing so because both our (or Sony) and Borders branding will be visible to you at the time you register), or 

(ii) you register a new account with us after October 11, 2007, and complete any one of the following actions before you purchase or download content using that account: 

(a) redeem a prepaid card, gift card or promotional code that displays both our (or Sony) branding and Borders branding; 

(b) redeem a prepaid card or gift card or promotional code that displays only our (or Sony) branding which was purchased or received from a Borders retail store or a Borders online retail location (a "Borders Store"); 

(c) you tell us that you heard about us through Borders or that you purchased your Sony Reader device from Borders; or 

(d) you download software that you received from a Borders Store or at a web page that contains both our (or Sony) and Borders branding. 

By taking any these actions, you agree that the Personal Information and other information you previously or thereafter provide to us in accordance with this Privacy Policy (or that was previously or is thereafter collected from you by us in accordance with this Privacy Policy) will also be provided to Borders for Borders' use in accordance with its privacy policy. We do not control Borders' use or treatment of information you provide (or that Borders collects from you). Therefore, before you take any of the actions described above or otherwise agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, you should consult the Borders privacy policy by visiting https://beta.bordersstores.com/online/store/CustomerServiceView_privacypolicy (which is incorporated herein by this reference) to determine your rights with respect to Borders' use and treatment of your Personal Information. If Borders notifies us of any material changes to its privacy policy, we will notify you by changing the "Privacy Link" on the Service to indicate the date the policy was last updated, for at least 30 days following the material change(s).

Borders may contact you with marketing messages if you affirmatively agree to receive such messages from either Borders or "our partners". You must communicate with Borders directly if you decide you no longer wish to receive communications from Borders or if you wish to amend or change the Personal Information or other information that Borders has obtained from you. 

**4. _Canadian Customers._** With respect to the Services offered and provided to residents in Canada, the practices and policies below are intended to comply with the Canadian Federal Governments Personal Information Protection and Electronic documents Act of 2000, as well as the privacy standards implemented by the Canadian Standards Association in its 1996 Model Code for the Protection of Personal Information, CAN/CSA-Q830-96. If you are a resident of Canada, the policies and practices set forth below supplement our general Privacy Policy and this Supplement thereto and apply to our handling and treatment of your Personal Information. With respect to our treatment of your Personal Information, if there is any conflict between any of the practices and policies set forth below and any other practices or policies that may otherwise apply, the terms of this Section apply to you.

**_Accountability._** We are responsible for the Personal Information under our control. If your Personal Information is shared with third party processors or marketing partners (i.e., Borders), we will use reasonable commercial efforts to require such third parties to maintain comparable levels of protection for your Personal Information. In addition, we have: (a) implemented procedures to protect your Personal Information (as set forth in this Privacy Policy); (b) established procedures to receive and respond to complaints and inquiries; and (c) communicated these practices and policies to our staff.

**_Identifying Purposes._** We will use reasonable commercial efforts to notify you of the purposes for which your Personal Information is collected and used at or before the time we collect it, as further set forth in this Privacy Policy and we will collect Personal Information to meet legal and regulatory requirements. Unless required by law, we will not use or disclose Personal Information we have collected from you for any materially different purpose, without first identifying and documenting the new purpose in amendments or modifications made to our Privacy Policy as permitted by the terms of this Privacy Policy or by notifying you directly if your Personal Information will be used for a purpose not previously disclosed to you. Even if we cannot obtain your consent in advance, unless one of the exclusions in our Privacy Policy require otherwise, we will use reasonable commercial efforts to advise you afterwards.

**_Consent._** We provide you with the information necessary to make an informed judgment to consent to our intended use, collection and disclosure of your Personal Information, except where inappropriate, unattainable or otherwise required by law or order of a court. In certain circumstances, Personal Information may be collected, used and/or disclosed without your advance knowledge or consent, if our action is, in our reasonable judgment: (a) in your interest; (b) necessary to protect persons or property (tangible or intangible) (c) if seeking your consent might defeat the purpose (e.g., an investigation into a breach or violation of law) or (d) in regard to collection of a debt, compliance with any legal or judicial order or compulsion or as otherwise required by law. In determining the most appropriate form or means of obtaining your consent, we will consider the sensitivity of particular Personal Information we seek to collect, use or disclose. Finally, we will not require you to consent to any collection, disclosure or use of Personal Information beyond what we require to fulfill the purposes we identify to you. Of course, subject to any legal restrictions or requirements, you may withdraw your consent at any time as described in our Privacy Policy. 

As documented above, some customers (including Canadian customers) will have their Personal Information shared with and disclosed to Borders for marketing and administrative purposes. Although we make no representations whatsoever regarding how Borders will use, manage, treat and maintain your Personal Information, we have used reasonable efforts to require that Borders have a privacy policy and institute measures and procedures to protect the Personal Information of its users, both direct and indirect. We encourage you to review Borders. Privacy Policy which can be accessed at the URL set forth in Section 3 above.

**_Limiting Collection._** We do not collect Personal Information indiscriminately and we only collect Personal Information using fair and lawful means. We collect only the Personal Information we believe is reasonably necessary to fulfill the purposes we identify to you.

**_Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention:_** Except as otherwise specifically set forth in our Privacy Policy, we will not use or disclose your Personal Information for purposes other than those permitted by our Privacy Policy (i.e., compliance with law, court order, with consent, etc.) and we will only retain your Personal Information as long as necessary, subject to legal and audit record-keeping requirements. We will also maintain reasonable and systematic controls and practices, in compliance with law, for information and records retention and destruction which apply to Personal Information no longer relevant or required for such identified purposes.

**_Accuracy of Personal Information:_** You are responsible for helping us keep your Personal Information accurate, complete and up-to-date and we will do our part to maintain the accuracy of Personal Information you provide to us and minimize the possibility that outdated information may be used to make decisions about you or your Account. However, please note that we do not update our customers. Personal Information on a routine basis. We will update your Personal Information within a reasonable time if you expressly request us to do so and/or provide us with updated Personal Information.

**_Security Safeguards:_** We will protect Personal Information by various security safeguards reasonably appropriate to the sensitivity of the Personal Information, which may include physical, organizational and technological measures. Employees with access to Personal Information are required, as a condition of employment, to respect the confidentiality of Personal Information.

**_Openness:_** We will make certain information about our policies and practices relating to the management of Personal Information available to you, including: (a) the contact information you may use for purposes of inquiring regarding your privacy and this Privacy Policy, and (b) the means by which you can gain access to your Personal Information in our records. We use reasonable efforts to try and make information available to assist you in making informed choices regarding the use of your Personal Information.

**_Individual Access:_** Upon written request, we will inform you if we have disclosed your Personal Information to third parties and we will give you the ability to review your Personal Information that we may have in our records. If you make a specific request to review your Personal Information, we will make your Personal Information available within a reasonable period of time, at minimal or no cost to you. However, you should note that we will not allow you to review Personal Information if doing so would or is likely to reveal Personal Information: (a) of a third party; (b) which includes or would reveal confidential or sensitive commercial information; (c) in violation of any attorney/solicitor-client privilege; (d) obtained in the course of a formal dispute resolution process; (e) associated with the investigation of a breach of any agreement; or (f) if doing so would violate any law or court order. We will always advise you of the reasons if we deny your request to review your Personal Information. Prior to making Personal Information available for your review, you will be required to provide sufficient identification and comply with our security procedures (which may include executing a confidentiality statement/agreement) before we authorize you to review your Personal Information. If you find that any Personal Information in our records is inaccurate or incomplete, you must notify us in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and we will amend it as needed within a reasonable period of time.

**_Challenging Compliance:_** If you are a Canadian resident, you may address any inquiries or concerns regarding our compliance with the Privacy Policy that applies to you, to privacy@am.sony.com or to the mailing address provided above. We will maintain procedures for responding to your inquiries or concerns which we may ask you to follow when you make an inquiry or have any complaint. We will make reasonable efforts to investigate such complaints, will inform you of any determination we make in response to a complaint you make and we will take such appropriate measures as are necessary to address such complaints, consistent with our obligations under our Privacy Policy as it applies to you.

**5. _Definitions._**

**"Account"** refers to any account that you have registered with the Service. 

**"eBook Service"** means our online eBook store available at www.ebookstore.sony.com (or its successor) or accessible through the eBook software client. 

**"The eBook Store from Sony at Borders"** means the version of the eBook Service that is co-branded by us and Borders.
